Right you can start...everybody thanks for coming.
...in the session I wanted to
...a little bit of washer search one of the services in the actual platform my name is
...asteroid work on the on...search team and my goal
...today is to cover both laude
...search...and also called to integrated into applications bulls mobile, mobile and
applications and I'm going to these us...as possible we build a couple of...
encourage everybody to ask questions on-the-spot as much as I can edges answer them as we
go we can...answer them in context so, thinking about why
...if you...applications you run your phone or you use in
your computer most of apps that have any sort of content from tweets
to documents to customer relationship management entries to your contact to
recipes or restaurants the weighing you interact with
...this in of reasonable volume...consumer is usually search
...bing google and others attentions has shown that we can actually
find anything across the whole web using just a quick search so it's only not to take the
...for to applications as well where data may not
be publicly surface so you can actually be index with being google or
it may need to be presenting ways...is not appropriate for a public search engine or for any other reason you want your
own local the search solution so as research
...offering in the asher platform that allows you to create a
...great search experiences in your applications.
So, we want to do today is I have three goals I want to give you a sense of what
it takes to get search...and running...research.
I talk about some of the specifics of web obscene mobile apps give
you like show you a few things running give you a few ideas and how to leverage...these
are different mediums have different interesting things and also different constraintsI also want to talk a little bit
about personalization and tuning how you can use search to create
better experience experiences for...and also to drive your business objectives
...ranking so,
let's start by talking about how do we get search off the ground how do we start?
So, typical flow for search is
...isolation you usually do it...the rest of your job but you need to provisions
search capacity provision assert service this is through for most of the are asher services as well you go to the
port earlier use api for that once you have it into create...
an index and tell us a little bit about what you want to index then you get need to get data into a thing
I'm finally you get to do searches usually integrated into your application so,
let's...into the steps and,
also how do we think about build...application around these very rarely you...and isolation you'll
...you...storesyou have buckets components another pieces
...make-up the whole thing rather than walk-in walk into these...isolated piece.
So, let's start by talking about provisioning.
The top-level resource that you create when you start working with
asher search is a search service such services that uses
global capacities these when you probation how much search capacity you want in terms of
course per second in terms of document...and things in terms of storage and,
you select a region so you say where in which in which of all the...we support you
...your data and sometimes if you multiple of them you can define multiple of them across,
across many...services inside have a number of things...have keys and index says and
data sources and a few other things we'll discuss later supervision one of these things usually
during exploratory phases when you go to a portal just do new there...walk
...minute and, these things also records function...exposed
to the through the...management api so often for production
...into bw use the management api to...
provision search capacity you can just call them directly or have arm templates and use them templates to
probation maybe search along with a number of all...you might have...part of your deployment?
The search service is also this called since...of capacity is what you used to manage...
of the service you can start small and then ask maybe document size increases or maybe
have a...workload where there's these some weeks in the year where you how like very high queries
per second number and then other times a year with these things slows down so then you can
dial the capacity you have on your on you provision...your service to copier
...to follow your capacity needs so-you...continue to get
could latency when you needed but you need to pay extra when you when you don't?
So, let me switch over real quick and let's take a quick look at what provisioning looks like the portal?
So, I have a provision service here but let me show you how we looks like when you start from scratch
so, if you go...new portal to ...
In storage you'll see the
research into their supervision you services you can go there big...
Conceive...to get excellent so, we offer two-tier is a free
...here fortitude is great for experimentation allows you to
has all the same capabilities in terms of functionality ...the
...here but I you get there's one in every subscription but you have to you have to pay for it you can pick
all usually you because I research group and then you need to because it was a solution where
...it and finally you get
typical location where you want where you want to service located...is?
these are all this so all these decisions are static decisions everything else you can change later but
...research group so on your make it here and
...here until you're done with service so, into one more thing.
The...second so,
right now we support a...for us to in europe and to in asia and
...in...so, you know, go over time we have we have better region
coverage once you have...provisions and them this would come...the open on one england.
Once you...provision would you get to do is if it's a free service then you can manage the rest of
...configuration there's not much to do service itself is a standard service then you get to manage
the scale so in this case the free service by for
...services I can get sorry for standard services I get to go here and,
dial-up and down the capacity of the service we
surface capacity in two dimensions replicas on partitions as you can see there think of...says
...search units that you can use into ways you can...them
come from one next to the other and create more capacity for documents so each unit
...fifty million documents and, they and they grow linearly so if you need thirty million you get to
you produce even sixty you can put...so on you get between one and twelve
of those and then if you need more replicas for-you if you more
queries per second you can use more replicas for that so read think of replicas
effectiveness copies of your data so we may take a little bit longer to write the doin'
updates but doing reads we only into bright...from one of them so we can...them in the end
...you get is this rectangle of replicas times petitions and these your total
capacity and this is completely elastic you can change these at any point and you can
change these online while we're doing written rights to your data ...
If you want knee-high availability
nalyze to replicas to get read availability and these three if you want...readability so,
you get to choose maybe...smaller app or in your dev environment you can say
...don't care about availability oceans I...something that is more affordable and it
...have a big deployment...I may say no I want
...per seconds on by the way I...one-eighteen...I may one more capacity.
So, great so once you
...once you...you have a starting point and then either now later you can
to in the capacity you get you get for the system.
So, now we have...servicing...a search servicing
place next thing that we have to think about these the shape of our index
...each search service can have one or more indexes and think of index like
a table is the thing where you put data and, the has many of the elements of a table like if we
...schema...the...I...things that relate to
...index like whether or not courses enabled what are the search...search options
...to index so on and I'll drill into a details of that in a minute the scheme itself I go to
an example immediately after these but it's a pretty usual stuff, you know,
feel this...fields have data types have names one of...key so on and,
then they have a bunch of search specific
information the reason why we have a schema is because when it comes to...is not the
kind of functionality what which is kind of hold your data give us a date and you...
more like we need to understand how you expect us to process you information,
for example, what attributes of the document...given as you want us to break apart so we
search we can search on later or what attributes uone do...has which are going to do structure
...filtering later that way we can create appropriate
underline data structures to dual of these fast?
There are also specific the specifics of search that
are beyond indexing their things like linguistics and, I'll talk more about linguistics in a minute but
...comes to search we kind of need to understand the specifics
of the language of the content on the languages of the content and same thing with things like the
gestures and scoring profiles which are very specific to surgeon we need to know so these are things you
define schema time and you use a different pointing
in your application so let's work on what it looks like
to define schema and, we'll explore a couple of options for this so usually
...exploratory face you often want...these important because it's a great way to this...what
you can do well before you commit to write a bunch of called in search would you can do in the portal.
So, there ...so you can create new indexes.
The first usually first thing...which fields you want
defining that index you need to have at least...field you can change the name but you need to have one fielded
will used to identify each one of the documents and then you can are you can add more.
More feels to...index is usual stuff there's been a basic types
...to interesting types nation to the usual suspects like numbers and the and dates and
strengths is we support collection of strings this is very common using search for things like
tags or anything that looks like a structure list of things you want to collect and,
the rone is we have first-class support for geospatial information
...these little more detail later but in terms of index definition you can say that something is
a geo point and then we'll...appropriately what...index you want to tell us things like us I
...before like is this field retrieval low you want to...it to
the want to facets on it and, take a couple of these so I can show you a couple
of options solicit...and...the woman...everything so,
you can you can configure what kind of language you want I'll get back to language in a minute and you can also
...suggest there's so-if you want-to havel to complete you can you can configured data complete options
...here so...creating indexes like this is very convenient and expiration again because
...you can create one of these maybe...use fiddler any other of this http
...tools to explore the functionality...get a sense of what you want
...we did with the search service once you're ready to create and up often you want more
...process and often you'll just use the api to create the services what
...index as well as you can just do it as part of your application deployment so,
let me let me start by doing one of those so what I do is
...the rest of the talk I'll have a couple of applications running puddle as, you know,
reproduce heard these so,...national we now have...offering and up service includes why
...mobile apps different ways to supportdifferent,
different front-ends for your app and one of the great things and...of these unification is at the bach
...are very similar so we get to reuse the same patterns and same functionality in both the
mobile app backhand ...ops so, I'll do a little bit of back and forth between these so you can
...of convex...let's start with the web...
So, let's say that as part of my web application I want to create indexes easily
...exist...on start...check everything and if it's not
there I'm going to create them so the way you start like if you're writing
application dot net like I'm doing here the best way to interact with
...search is we have.
A...library...you can find in the
...get ripple so just go grab the new
...from the aerial make your life significantly easier in our
...you can just use the rest api you'd find the right packages from the ones that are available in this case
every have the library here so what I want to do is first want...myself like an
entry pointing...xmpp more real application you probably do...injection framework something like this and create you
and...yourself an entry point...the search index client.
Search client and what I want to do is
...initialization...and if needed to create and index so let me go
grab ventricle home here so you have to which me type whole bunch?
So, of decently support a little bit what I want...do is version
when I create the entry point to api which is a search service client and grab some settings like
this service name and the keys from configure then I'm going to create and index
get to indexes in a minute and implement that out.
And, then I want to grab a client specific that just kind of
...to...index and then...that...my singled and I'm going to using the rest of the
app the way the rest of my application doesn't carry-over convex and keys
or things like that all of these capturing initialization set up a dependency that you can use a
proper injection framework to use later and you have to worry about what are you indexes so on that
...that knowledge is confined to
...initialization phase so now let's create and index...bring the...then I walk through it.
So, what this does is it says I have a I want to have an index...sessions that like if you
...who here minutes ago like I have a couple of other indexes but we'll have that one yet
so, if...not there they want to create...index
...create api about a bunch of fields and these correspond to what we saw in the
portal minutes ago and the data said that
...have is I have I took the all...from build
...interesting to due to build something where you can probably correct to these like you have
...session to build conference and how bunch of sessions and somebody can come over and say
okay build-up for build and one of the pieces that we load expected...have good search so,
you can see that some of these I said this field troubles of them are solvable...a mix of types so
on uci set up a suggested so,
this is a suggests there is the building-block to use for...you know-how you go to
being google start typing and we all kind of wait for a second see what see what happens so,
that's something that everybody out kind of has been trained to expect so we provide
building blogs the make...for you to build...your application as what?
Great so, now we have ...any solicitation will what's going to happen is going to runs
...and if there's no index going-to go ahead and create...one question.
Great...question is covered what about scheme updates so, we allow you to
add fields within allow you to change fields the reason for that is like
search indexes and index and...optimized for retrieval so,
changing, changing the options of existing...usually means we
...everything we debate often whether or not we should do every index you should...in...
I think we would make people's life...here if we did some maybe...we'll do it right now we don't so
...you need to...field then or change and option that you have to of the index and recreated if you need to
...fields at any time and...they'll just default to
...and you can add information later the other thing is these...do very well and sparse,
sparse data so you can...no...thanks
over time if you don't want to...the index and still just...information from a column.
I guess this will work much better when we actually call it so let's do
it upsurge here right so we have we have an index set up so.
...have an index I want to point out one line-item here and really into it a
little bit there's a choice...the and talk about which is linguistics like one of the items
in these linguistic is an aspect that you
maybe another convex may or may not important but in the context of search.
We need to understand what's going on and this is something we can make very few assumptions like I'm sure there's many
folks in this room that build applications a...run on english or done right...at all so,
then let me...double-click...a little bit and look at more details if you think about
how even the most basic functionality of search the first thing we have to do when...search
is break words apart and that's it sounds like piece of cake until you realize
that languages have...pieces and, then is not so piece of cake and,
then there is there are some languages like this...a little bit in english but there are...for example,
romans languages
are heavily inflicted languages as a fuzzy way of saying...just too many ways to say things ...you know,
for example, romans language includes the in spanish french...for someone spanish
...for goal has like maybe fifteen inflections sixteen fiction some ridiculous number
they're very regular so...hard to catch-all the forms of it and they body we things
...gender and...and combinations of them so,
these things are tricky even...in english there are things like do not all the verb not all the...announcer
...regular with respect to...some form so, you have to have awareness of
all these details so,...search include support for fifty languages
out-of-the-box where you can just use a default very general-purpose
and, that we call them analyzers because they do more than just
...breaking the process the do a number of things with the input and this is terminology borrow...from
...scene which is ...open-source ...of...the search library so,
we offer standard analyzer just worse like uses genetic,
genetic I'll functionality to deal with language and that's okay that's pretty...western languages not so much and
...then we ledges
to specific languages we are surface to sets we...seen analyzer
said this is a well-known in the industry we surface m asses so that if
you already have investments in the area or if, you know, them well and you want...function...can get the
...also do many of them when appropriate for the language they do stemming,
stemming is way to get the...and...the words of up a prefix of the word that
...the same across variations of the word, for example, when you have variations in number?
...languages like english is really effective we also went and took like
a we when we working on building search we were looking around to see how we
could get more language coverage and...out that the office guys know a bunch of all these to have the word
grammar backhand and...colors and things like that for many languages the bing...also
noble a bunch of these and...how the thing that we went and, into...into search so,
this allows us to a have more language coverage but,
also give you a different options on certain languages depending on what you want
to optimize for like...one concrete example of dc the microsoft analyzers
...this limitation for a number of languages...and it's a little bit on the details
...but it actually has an effect on...apps where sometimes
...good volume of data and then snuff vocabulary...people which is fine with the looking for
using the words in the dataset when they search but sometimes either is a dataset smaller you
have...regal problems like you usually don't find the documents are looking for within the
...then you want to be more aggressive about finding
were variations and things like that limitation is a way to find all word variations
understanding language so you can you catch things like variations intense that are not regular so
you can't...to understand...we're talking about there's no there's no obvious choice here there's no one
...better than the other this are different so, again, this is the...you choose through,
through experimentation
we show you a couple of examples to illustrate the difference between these...
first to show you these...for so you would.
The index I'm going to use to demonstrated so I have this index
that is simplified version of what we're going to use for the rest of the app that what it does
is these...not like me today so,what it does
is I took all the session abstracts and I index them three times or
...three fields one of them using standard analyzer node
language aware the other one using ...you seen english analyzer after one
...microsoft...that's the way we can have contrast the...run the
...while we wait for these and then what I do
...I wrote the sketchy ist ever web page
...to just try this out so you're not going to impressed by the visuals but let me
...few things so if I said for something like web then we'll
...bunch of service all is just a wall of
...across-the-board and there's not a lot about the ability to that but let me pick on something more specific like,
for example, the word find so, you can see there is a little bit of variation and part of
it is for things like inflections and one thing I can do is
I'm using highlight there's which is one of the features that we have where you can
ask the system why do we much particular thing so if I hover over these things you can see
that pound you can choose what separator you want the cy do-too-much
particular a particular document so this for example, this
...an instance where...fragile if you should say tight fines
...to find then find is
like even if we don't do this but we don't do prefix search by default but even if
...not a prefix of...you just don't find...stuff so,
tiny things like that variations number and these case reasons on who you're
talking about which is getting the way of recall and this may or may not be a problem in some cases
find has another problem which is any regular verbs?
So, if you want to say found
define even though probably none of these guys say found anywhere
...say find we still we still can locate them so, this...in
mostly in verbs in most languages but you see happening now in...sometimes
...a very contrived scenario turns out that is one talk...a word...in it so,
if you if I say miles that I've I...everywhere here's one thing you can see out of
what mechanical streaming does so...doesn't exist.
But, ... state...usually what they do is they chop off the front of the...sometimes just a little bit
...still find it and, then if you say my eyes which is a plural form then...only find if you do
...this is not...a good thing is usually good if you have
regal problems but again it means you'll find a lot of stuff so sometimes you may just
get...of...and if you have good polarizing ranking then
this is counterproductive you have good ranking
...is good stuff because you get good recall and the same time would ranking to get the...it.
All right so that's languages so now we have an index we picked languages for some of the columns we might have left
the default for others and, the next step is how do we get data into the index.
There are two main options to the get data into the index you can push data into
...or you can let us pull into the index.
So, the first option is ...offer and api the same
rest api where you can define indexes and who gets to you should searches cuss
...point where you can send us barge...requests...up to a thousand
...like action seen them what actions can be...or
upload the lead so on you can send them at any time we process them...synchronous
...not...is not a...assistant models so once we acknowledge back
to you that we took it doesn't mean that...right away we may take a few seconds to
re index because we have to modify welcoming them to the section...to modify the of the
underline indexes to make it searchable may take a few seconds and then you'll see it but you can do this
...your cadence ...things happen your application this question?
The question is a way to know...data has been index null and,
...I guess yes you can search for it but
...like you have to know like a unique thing that especially
...record is particularly
tricky because you have to search for the difference which is hard to identify we
...currently provide a way to this we thought about providing like tracking values the challenge
with that is that you may like in the time you turn around from the update and go to check if
it completed you may have...interleaved update so, it's unclear what state are
...so, we haven't done we haven't done anything about that yet?
When it comes to push indexing...is ...a couple of ways you...approach these one is
...happen you can goal turn-around and
...index an example of these maybe replication back-end you get the update you push them into
the database at the same time you will push them into the index or you put them in a q and you have a worker
the picks up from the...updating index...I...about that is that changes in the
index happen...less...hopping in the application so for things that
where the user may make a change and immediately turn around and see the changes there that's a good
potter this otherwise people think the update dion work or something so you
...do something where you do it relatively quickly it also means that since you
were calling us the data can be anywhere so they
it has to make it into index but we don't care if you got it from some other asher service if you
buy it from unknown premise piece of code that actually even the called indexing goes not running on
ashes running on your own servers or even smaller cloud thing
we'd like as soon as you manage to called us we don't care where you're coming from...music
and index anything in terms of patterns wanting the fits really well here if you want more of a periodic thing
...if you're pulling from a...is so, web apps and nownext thanks to the
up service integration storymobile apps as well...thing called web jobs for those
...media we what jobs...great way to run arbitrary background code
...application in addition to the interactive directed called so...you?
If you want...
Indexing web jobs would you can do is in any roller.
Mobile or web application you can go to the...and then there is a way to...
A...you web job project usually web jobs are simple consul apps ditches
deployed in a way that get running the background and then you can choose to use the
...more integration whenever you can just run on your own a simple example have a simple
example recreated here where.
order is to program...just new in the host waiting for it and then I have a simple function
where during initialization I get my own client and have a see the different index here they
...has had set up and then what you can annotate
methods we particular three years and then triggers just do a lot
of work for you in this case how this three-year that says...new blobs in these
...storage blog container just...me and here you can use a
blog type and then you get all information about the blob or in the case in the similar case where,
you know, it's just some text you can just have a string and then they'll just extract the text and then pass you
...dexter function ...actually pretty completed like if you
...exceptional retry later they do place message handling is actually really good solution we've been
...work...the awesome thing that...locally as what because it's just a consul apps it's very easy to
debug and...and you can deployed as part of your application so,
what we are actually doing here is?
Whenever we get a new blading will catch blob will build a batch...case
...one document batch.
When we create a new id we take the content and we make-up a
new field called date and them which is called index and that which is
...two-story from succeeds...a few seconds later you can search it and,
this is I mean you should an example of how this looks like when runs storage
explorer I have a container here with a couple of blobs the also keep track of what blogs they
...went through and call-you foresee...to your and...staff?
Let's create a new blog here.
And, then sort...pinpoint here so if I run this guy.
Then on start-up the risk...detect changes and then what they do is every few minutes I think
the windows incoming up-to-the-minute so it's...real-time thing but it's pretty regular then they'll detect
changes and then call your function to kind of catch up the one thing to think
to think about is in this case if you have something where...added maybe a few a minute or a few
...then you can do something like this because the permeability so cling linking...you can see
...a content of...blob...build a badge and then we'll call index to
...bunch in the client...if we didn't get any exceptions ...
just give five and if I go here now?
If a few minutes or a few seconds we check again statistics are not updated real-time once
the updated the here which...see like...document here like a document...the three because we
...documents as they happen.
I...the portal...up a little bit.
So, anyway, so, the great...push then is you can get
data from anywhere you can push data...your own pace and you can
...things together and, if you have something like this one did regularly you can use web jobs if
you want to attractively you can...with the rest of europe so how the...what if you don't want to do
this work and you want us to do it for you so we have this other thing
...indexes...
index serves our mechanism that allows us to do the bulk of the work for indexing
for-you so the way...work is we have a set of specific data sources we support
...support the sequel database and asher nash's...
be you can also do it without from the m if you set up the if I was right and,
we also support document db out-of-the-box when you create...would usually point
...this tour you give us specific data container like
a table recollection review and then you give us a policy
a policy includes things like how often to check for changes and how
to change detection and deletion detection and, we...information will do everything else so you can
set up and just fight it off and then we'll regularly execute these and,
put information...there are ...indexes and indexes of
these separate things that are a number of interesting scenarios a come out of these ...so,
for example, like the trivial
...you have...index you have a data source let's...have a document db database and have a collection
in it so you can pulled from there and set it up on the index and then you set it up
...forget...go watch it to make sure it's in good shape and you can monitor into portal?
But,...you can do all combinations like, for example, you can have to data sources to
indexes same index so...an example of...maybe you have your dayton
documentaries you push from there but then maybe you have these analytics loop that maybe
gobs the laws and things like that computes interesting signals are tags of this classification for your
users and then you turn around and that after all that analyses put that
...a...table and periodically pulled from...table...
into the same index we use merge operations for these so as long as the keys line-up maybe, you know,
one of them of...the first by columns and the one of the second two columns or
...so there's a way of consolidating multiple data streams into a search
...index to construct the whole experience the opposite also works you can
have multiple indexes with multiple indexes...the same data...of these let's say one multiple
sub services in multiple regions around the globe either for redundancy
...for latency optimization you can do is you can
...your primary storing a single place what they have multiple search services each one
...index appointing all of the same data store so they all follow the changes
...hub in the primary store il independently
populate their own indexes so there are many ways you can kind of a range these into workable scenario.
Let me show you...how do we set this up and what this look like...portal?
So, first of all I mentioned if you have this is...a different service I...what
...set-up and a run for a while so when you have...you can monitor the indexes index...
the...you can see success and failure rate because these things running the background so you need to find a way to know
know-how to how they're doing you can monitor them through the api or you can come to the portal and you can
see execution times and frequency and if...errors you can go here and see the
adverse...happened in the last execution or the last few executions.
So, following the pattern that we had before it's actually as part of treating the
...create and index are.
So, let's...
I'm bringing this piece of code this does is it creates to pieces and index are
...there's three moving parts...index and we already have one of those
...source the defines how do we get to...source of the data and then there's the index
which is the policies and the connection point between the source and...you create and
a data source the things you say to give a name so we can mention it in
thein other parts of the system...type today you can...say two things here you can say
documentary or...can...asher sequel as we are more sources you'll see them show up
here you can...container in this case the...in the context of...to be the
...a collection name in sql it could be like a table or view.
The other thing we support is if you don't say anything which is
...pulled from the table or in this case
the collection but you can also give us an arbitrary query which means you can do things like
filter's stuff before...makes it less maybe you have a thing a column that says, you know,
search radius null or you can transform let's say you're input it's
needs and it's in the case of...we may need some flattening in the case of sql you may want to do some
...normalization often use these...but if you want you...you enlightened here
and...encapsulate the whole thing on the on the data source definition
...of course and then we'll ob movie to policies
we need to know how to detect the things changed and we need to know how to...the things
got deleted for change detection it depends on the data source we have if you targeting
...asher and
...tables we can usechange...mechanism that's built into
sequel there is very efficient it allows us to track inserts updates on the
...as well...works so, it's very convenient for these ...other thing we can do is going to high
...both in sql you can do role version...the...column
underscore ts the...decide that then we'll use that as way to detect when things
were new...modified and for...you can give a dumb stones you can give us a
field say called deleted or something like that you can say when they feel has these value then
conceded deleted from the next and then you can garbage collect them from your additional source ones,
you know, the we caught up and, finally the index are has name has a data serves...and
index so...brings all the parts together and has...in this case and saying, you know,
every ten minutes?
So, great so we have an index and we have an index are.
Let me update these pieces.
There so what we do during...then is we create an index create and index are
...don't...your...I'm resetting here because I did one before and
I want to make sure...said the state of index are if you re said that what that means is forget about your change
...information and start over and then...right here just because if not...have to wait you know,
for five minutes this is very convenient during iteration and dividing you can
...to schedule you can run index interactively?
at this point we have enough million...doing start-up this application should
not do anything interesting on the search side but you will it will.
...index and I would index...support
the really doesn't like me today but if you maybe you get into a better mood.
Let's see if I can show you the index.
...is going to index...minute so, the other thing I'm going to...one so,
what I'm doing here is...have a document...collection
That has ...sessions so my index are going-to-take
...from documentary...push into a index so let me quickly show you
the dogma explorer let me show you an example of a document so
these what a document looks like has like codec has a title
has an abstract a few tags speakers and an start time
...pm standard priest on their stuff so now all of that is in the search index.
So, what we want to do now is actually search for stuff we have the...index either we push
...we pulled ...index...and the next steps to search?
So, ...mechanics of search tend to be pretty simple because once you manage to get the
data in place then all you into...collect...requests and push them into...
research will if you...sayings specific about ranking...talk about ranking in a minute then was
just default ranking...use the frequencies of the words and things like that to find with
the most interesting documents and then return a set of matching...ranking order we support
simple primitives like plus-minus to take the search a little bit think of it does and
...query options kind of thing more than a
developers not query language is we have separately from these we have filters
and projections and sorting so one that is more like now would you would exposed to the user but
...would you use in addition to the user input if you want to filter sort things so,
what interesting...you have to make when you're searching is going to such from the client or even search from the
in the data you have needs to be secure is not public then the options clear you
...from...of...have to hide the keys you can't...if you can access from the client say
from the browser phone you can access index directly than everybody else
...in some cases turns out...your search indexes are very exposing all information...the
...there's nothing internal there in that case you may choose to do
it from the client you save a latency...so you...latency there and, you can do everything
like javascript or in case of the phone you can do...directly from a phone or more device the
other thing you can think about here is when you rendered search results
what you can choose what to pulled from the index and you can also choose to stashed things in...not searchable you can
...everything...allows you to do is you can stash information in the index
...rendering purposes even though it's not about search this says you
...primary store so for example,
if...search results uone maybe a picture and some description...you that you're not searching you can
...the url to it in a fielding search
...doing the in the search results and then...the...you can do full rendering without touching your primary
...and much is going to be much faster?
So, let's very quickly hook up hook up search here.
So, what I do for search is?
I have this very simple the page and this bring in a kind of a couple of building blocks to.
And, I walk you through each part that I'm bringing.
So, first thing I...a simple least.
We can...the results so let's put
this in here so what I do this is a small for this...amusing
...so I get to type I...a title...for review I'm just using what they
search the search primitive in the asher...returns which is a very
convenient molly has...for the hits on the documents...so on
so, what I'm doing here is for each kid gets...the title of the talk
...is the...talks and then the start time on the room?
The other thing that...have to think about isthere's a contest between where
it would be doing you rent new rendering these in big-screen for small screens say a mobile app
versus a web...in...tend to have especially if you're targeting the desktop you tend to have a lot more
real state and you want to use that to make navigation easier on the phone
or more devices you especially in the for your more...and,
usually a better off getting fancier...tell you process input rather than trying to get...on what
...display and make people navigate because there's just no real-estate for that so let's start with
the web version amid and for the web version of it what unless you might have some good real-estate
...to facets and I'm going to show you what...thirty-minute
so,do facets you'll see how the all of these comes together...that I'm going
to facets and speaker's tags?
On start time.
So, now they have some html here.
Let me bring in the method that would actually do a search so what I'll do is
I'll go to the default controller the have anything interesting there yet.
And,...I'll say is...a search parameter and if there is a search in
a input then I construct
such parameters options whereas say I want to top twenty.
I want to total count as well and also include
...filter a filter's usually not surface...I'm doing is here so we get so I can illustrate
...point but these are things like imagine you have documents...for publishing yes null or you have the
...you want to say only a documents...have these user may minute so, fingers
...structure...separate from search...kind of the soft thing what is this is like...classing
...statement and then what I'm doing is I'm just calling remember that we stashed out the index client
in nbc up so I'm calling documents that so chasing
...the search...that I got from the...the parameters and...token?
So, let me...guy who actually forgot to detail ...remember
I mention facets so facets out a way of calculating subtitles of things that matched
...a very common construct using in search navigation so,
what I can do is here I can indicate the list of fields that
I'll when they need to be enables for...doing index definition that I
...facet on for this particular requests I can change these from request, request?
...do speakers whoops tags.
And, ...time.
Right so if now I go here and do a
web then I get results for web so what that means is the data made it so we
create...index data made from the documentaries tore into the asher search index
and now we get the search results ranked by relevance web...words the relevance
...awash and, also all these things I've been calling facets so this is the hid count by
categories very commenting things like e-commerce websites...things like that and there's a
very effective navigation metaphor because you can get a sense of in this case and all the speakers and all the tags
...timesyou can do like if we get more specific on the content of these like
...say like linux then we get a few lest hits but
you can still see...tags...a few start and timeswho get even more specific?
Then you'll see...is...research these
...cussing description and then the rest start to rank less and less probably because how the
...should or search some...in their.
In...content and, in addition...research again in addition to these I can
...very common thing is to the real allow people to drill into these...almost...mystic
before you talk and when you...you get only the ones there is a combination of search plus
a filter to create these experience what I can...down and things and,
then come back up and then I can do the same I
can see these five that much of this time...only three of these time maybe a big this one so on?
So, these an example where the mechanics of
...upsurge...a couple of lines of code you get how...you come to have the...there on the by
...to do it.
So, similar to these.
If you want to have all the complete and these.
Mechanics are very similar so I already indicated which feel...complete what I can do is
...entry...my controller for called suggest api to of the search api
bus would the input the use of bustle far a few options like in this case enabled
fussing merging and return these down to the client this case and return
...and this allows me to use j queries
...complete we just ...how do you I depends on, you know,
depends on your app and what you're doing in this case I'm doing something very simple where I'm just doing the default
...experience?
And, ...to load so now when I start typing?
I get times I get suggestions and what is the I may be looking
...if I get more specific then I'll get more specific on the suggestions as
well so this is a way to be and these are thanks people tend to
expect surgeon we make sure...easy to wired them up?
So, at this point we got the basics of searching place.
Like I want to highlight some specifics though there's a lot in common when you
build meanwhile mobile apps...if you sign up...because a lot of the back-end...common you can use the same
comptroller model you can use you can use web jobs...use is...duties and...so on but,
there are some differences that you want you want acknowledge if you're
...targeting one or the other in web...different the amount of real
...and you can depend on the use of giving more input in general because...only have more space but input
is easier to do...keyboard so on mobile apps
...because the input is trickier ...less you have
...are less ...to operate so on so usually you're best bet for
...context take us few words as you can then use the context for the
...sometimes you-know-who...use threes, you know, what time is it, you know, where the user u
...you application ask for all these options when you created then you get access to all these convex and you
can use this context to make such better without making your and use at work
...also like one kind of...I just demonstrated
...suggestions in the phone that doesn't always work...like usually predictive word input
...very effective a and these things are different you kinda have to explore which one you
...depended on context so one option for input is to use voice and,
depending on your platform there's different, different levels of support for voice in the case of
windows we have proton out...has a great extensibility model and this is a great
march with search because in the end if you think about...even today windows phone inputting one the
...and extensibility infrastructure for it and gets much better in windows ten and,
you think about interactions with an agent like rotunda usually you to get
it somehow and then you say a bunch of words and that's when you have to work with a bunch of words
so...are not...natural target for that unless you really the restrictive cover you
...you can say if you want to take arbitrary input
then what you're looking for use what is a thing that I can give it a bunch of words
...with the realities of language variation and give-me-a-buzz sense of ranked
...number...search does so this very natural was kind of integration point between
doing voice input...things they could turn out and doing and, doing search a
...like I can and quickly show this working so I have an
example and show you and this is based on action example willing to put out there that has just a different data
sets so you can you-can pick it up if you if you're interested so you
...phone up?
To have a from here's and projected.
There and, this is a windows phone project and
in my data semis would have used the same search primitives were using before
...semis...an on the server also runs in windows apps
...I'm using to create a couple of search
experiences here one that takes a query I'm one that uses the context in this case time who
...person needs and, thenas part of the core...extensibility infrastructure when you can do is you can
define set of rules that...say what are the prefix is a
content should react to...application and once you have your in the context of application
then you can you can say what patterns you want to recognize so, if
we execute this guy.
Then...get deployed to the phone.
And, there's a couple of things we can do here.
And, this will be or...given a second.
So, one is you can just say find session and
tag something fine sure.
then we'll go find decisions and index and come back but, then we can do other things like,
you know, coming next is a very simple way to just give me sessions that are coming in the next tower
...a great way of not having to do a bunch of inputs and then if you are...would content you can do a good
...of thing I'm going to give it why...have this...accent so we'll see how that goes?
Build whiny sessions what...search.
nonsense but this involved with the build application so they actually could
...I'm sure the other ones similar but the...they have is actually pretty impressive and,
...a great way to do search input...now you can have an application that you invoked without
even running uses...present...and retire than say that word for your app
the belcher up and you say if you words and boom you have you have a search and sometimes
...searches no search you can do see you can say things like.
Build and what's coming next.
And, that's quite...contains...contains no...of the main is
just invoking the what's coming next you know, queries against query by time.
This is a great way to provide a and
...experience on a more devices the interesting thing about this is that
decomposes really well with good relevance because you want minimal input like in this case I
...what's next so how can we do things like what's next better so,
this is all sorry I forgot to mentioned nation to voice input location input
this just as important so, you know,
what you...the case of the build example is not
...compelling but if you're looking for a trailer or a shop or something like that then
...geospatial...is just as important?
So, this is a context were the same before
...to location and time and,
...having custom ranking to make a huge difference and there are a few
...see for this one is just data...in the files...we have a thing called
...profiles that allows you to...the...a couple of steps to builds I'm not going to
live here but ...coding provides a way to connect the dots you can say, for example,
things are happening soonermore relevant and things that...happening later on you can say by how much and,
these are based on data in the documents because
...personalize we have a thing called tag boosting that allows you to do is let's use build
ascended to describe these by example let's say every session has a has a set of times
...every user has tags and you can help...user because you pick them
or because using clustering and some machine learning technique we drive them out of your
prior conferences with...well or not well so on so
now we have them so that boosting allows you to boost documents when you
pass the search buses the types of the user and whatever wi-fi non empty intersection we like
...documents better that doesn't mean we're not going to offer documents don't have the tags means that we skewed towards
ones have the tag all the things being equal so, these are really powerful way to current to
...kind of a personalized experience for it
and finally you can do analytics where you can compute signals like, for example,
tags or popularity and feed that bucking to index and uses
...with all these things combined next time I'll pick up my phone and say what's coming
next our will do is based on the time based in the popularity of the session based
...my pry on my past history using
...boosting and give me a very kind of custom experience for my specific preferences and this is
what you expect from search very little input great very compelling answers so,
users will be can surprised by...suggest in the right thing in the right context.
just...quick walk through what these things look like...usually when you have a full
...me to look like that you start by having traditional text in something like
...degree...generate a bunch of traffic that...your search index
but you also grab those logs and you can put them in something like whooping in asher
br hd...is a very non-threatening thing I know like...sounds like you had a deploy
whole cluster so on but it's actually very straightforward to do because they manage all the
deployment and the you can even use
...data factory to spin the cluster up announce you have to pay for it all the time so
there's very well thought out story where you can do heavy analytics without
becoming an expert...infrastructure and...a fortune and once you have these data you can
feed back into the index using the...model that we talked about before I make it
increasingly more relevant ossie application...more intense martyr.
So, with...recap so we
...provision services created indexes for those services then we...pushed or pulled
models to automatically bring the data or...bring data into index
defined a bunch of linguistics options that allows us to have better experiences for the language of
...targeting and then we created uri is...and
...drug research both in desktop a mobile devices including rotunda input to get have
...experiences and then...scoring profiles...and things like
that boosting analytics we created more relevant six more relevant experiences
...by understanding what they need...personalizing results for
...particular scenario so...that...a few resources here
...out here for question but before...for questions but first I want to say
thanks-very-much for listening and here on the rest of...cover great...of the bentley.